So now that you suffer through all these wonderful things like,
现在 你们在学习所有这些神奇的知识时可能倍感艰辛
pointers, and memory allocations.
例如 指针和内存分配
So, let me tell you the story of
我给大家讲个故事
the worst self-driving car bucket I ever caused and had to fix.
这是我经历过的最糟糕的无人驾驶车故障 我花了大力气才修好
Took me many months to find it.
故障定位就花了我好几个月
Okay. So we are, now back in 2005 driving Stanley,
好的 我们现在回到 2005 年驾驶 Stanley
the self-driving car, through the Mojave Desert.
这辆无人驾驶车 穿越莫哈维沙漠
And initially, we had one computer on board, and he was fine.
最初 车上有一台电脑 运行得不错
And then the computer was overloaded,
然后 电脑超载了
so we put a second computer on board.
因此 我们加装了第二台电脑
And as a result,
结果
as we found out every 40 miles,
我们发现 隔每 40 英里
the robot would see a fake wall of obstacle in front of it,
机器人都会判定在它前面存在一道假墙
engage in a crazy, crazy swerve,
结果就超级疯狂地转弯
and almost kill us, but felt like killing us.
我们快被逼疯了 感觉要崩溃了
And then we had to intervene and take over.
然后 我们不得不介入 并采用人工驾驶
And we knew the race was about 120 miles long.
我们知道 这场比赛长达 120 英里
So every 40 miles the robot would do this, we would not finish the race.
而每 40 英里 机器人就会出这样的问题 这导致了我们没法完成比赛
So what was it?
那么问题出在哪里呢？
So you're looking at the robot advance a mile,
我们检测了机器人 发现
it could be there and fine, and second, it doesn't.
第一台电脑工作正常 而第二台则有问题
And we were flabbergasted.
我们很吃惊
What ended up being is,
结果就是
we had put in a timer for how all the data is.
为此 我们放了一个计时器来记录数据的生成时间
They would give us a bound on how big an obstacle is.
这样 我们就会知道这个障碍的持续时间
Let's take this for granted for now.
现在 我们先不考虑这种做法的合理性
In moving to two computers,
回到两台计算机
we found that the clocks ran different speeds.
我们发现这两台计算机的时钟运行速度不同
Pretty common in many two computers.
这在很常见 毕竟这是两台计算机中
And we installed computer software,
我们安装了计算机软件 C++
C++, to synchronize these clocks.
来同步这两个时钟
And every one so often,
时不时地
the synchronization would set a clock value back.
这种同步设置可以将一个时钟值往回拨
Now a test that would be contingent on the time
由于测试取决于已经过去的时间
elapsed would not have a negative number because timeless was negative.
因此回拨的时钟值不可能为负
And that in conjunction with the vehicle bumping up and down over
而车辆碰到地面稍微凸起的地方 就会上下颠簸
a little hump caused a fake obstacle.
这和时钟问题相结合 就造成了一个假障碍
Now, that was brutal.
这个问题太折磨人了
It took us literally months to find it.
我们花了几个月的时间才确定故障
And we drove every day,
为此 我们每天开车
and every 40 miles or so we got this effect,
每 40 英里左右 我们就碰到这样的问题
and we couldn't figure out what's going on.
而且我们对原因一头雾水
Now, I'm telling you this story because,
我之所以讲这个故事 是因为
when you dive and become a software engineer,
在你深入学习并成为软件工程师的过程中
every little detail matters.
每一个细节都很重要
And you have to understand how memory allocation works,
而且你必须了解内存分配
how pointers work, how data structures work,
指针以及数据结构的工作原理
because if you don't,
因为如果你知道这些
and you allocate memory twice,
导致内存分配了两次
or you forget to free it,
或者忘了释放内存
at some point, you're self-driving car will fatally commit suicide, okay?
那么 在某个时间点上 你的无人驾驶车会出现致命的自杀行为
So, thanks for sticking with us,
所以 感谢你与我们一起坚持
and I hope you appreciate we just learned.
希望你能认识到我们刚刚所讲内容的重要性